<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>python - Tag - The Child is Father of the Man</title>
        <link>https://arvimal.github.io/tags/python/</link>
        <description>python - Tag - The Child is Father of the Man</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 00:00:00 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://arvimal.github.io/tags/python/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Callables in Python</title>
    <link>https://arvimal.github.io/posts/2017/08/2017-08-09-callables-in-python/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://arvimal.github.io/posts/2017/08/2017-08-09-callables-in-python/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Introduction A callable is an object in Python that can be called / executed when called with parantheses ( ). Classes and functions are callable.
Callables can be a class, a function, or an instance of a class. In simple terms, a class/function/instance/builtin is callable if it gets executed when called with parantheses ().
Example 1: In [1]: help() Welcome to Python 3.6&#39;s help utility!  -- content omitted -- -------- In [2]: int() Out[2]: 0 In [3]: callable(int) Out [3]: True In [4]: callable(help) Out [4]: True In [5]: def hello(): print(&#34;Howdy!]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Recursion - Algorithm Study</title>
    <link>https://arvimal.github.io/posts/2017/06/2017-06-27-recursion-algorithm-study/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2017 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://arvimal.github.io/posts/2017/06/2017-06-27-recursion-algorithm-study/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[_R_ecursion is a technique by which a function calls itself until a condition is met.
Introduction Loops or repetitive execution based on certain conditions are inevitable in programs. Usual loops include if, while and for loops. Recursion is an entirely different way to deal with such situations, and in many cases, easier.
Recursion is a when a function calls itself in each iteration till a condition is met. Ideally, the data set in each iteration gets smaller until it reach the required condition, after which the recursive function exists.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Selection Sort - Algorithm Study</title>
    <link>https://arvimal.github.io/posts/2017/02/2017-02-11-selection-sort-algorithm-study/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2017 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://arvimal.github.io/posts/2017/02/2017-02-11-selection-sort-algorithm-study/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[_S_election Sort is a sorting algorithm used to sort a data set either in incremental or decremental order.
It goes through the entire elements one by one and hence it&rsquo;s not a very efficient algorithm to work on large data sets.
How does Selection sort work? Selection sort starts with an unsorted data set. With each iteration, it builds up a sub dataset with the sorted data.
By the end of the sorting process, the sub dataset contains the entire elements in a sorted order.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Accessor and Mutator methods - Python</title>
    <link>https://arvimal.github.io/posts/2016/12/2016-12-18-accessor-and-mutator-methods-python/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2016 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://arvimal.github.io/posts/2016/12/2016-12-18-accessor-and-mutator-methods-python/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[A method defined within a class can either be an Accessor or a Mutator method.
An Accessor method returns the information about the object, but do not change the state or the object.
A Mutator method, also called an Update method, can change the state of the object.
Consider the following example:
[code language=&ldquo;python&rdquo;] In [10]: a = [1,2,3,4,5]
In [11]: a.count(1) Out[11]: 1
In [12]: a.index(2) Out[12]: 1
In [13]: a Out[13]: [1, 2, 3, 4, 5]]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Inheritance and super() - Object Oriented Programming</title>
    <link>https://arvimal.github.io/posts/2016/07/2016-07-01-inheritance-and-super-object-oriented-programming/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://arvimal.github.io/posts/2016/07/2016-07-01-inheritance-and-super-object-oriented-programming/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[_s_uper() is a feature through which inherited methods can be accessed, which has been overridden in a class. It can also help with the MRO lookup order in case of multiple inheritance. This may not be obvious first, but a few examples should help to drive the point home.
Inheritance and method overloading was discussed in a previous post, where we saw how inherited methods can be overloaded or enhanced in the child classes.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Abstract Base Classes/Methods - Object Oriented Programming</title>
    <link>https://arvimal.github.io/posts/2016/06/2016-06-14-abstract-base-classesmethods-object-oriented-programming/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2016 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://arvimal.github.io/posts/2016/06/2016-06-14-abstract-base-classesmethods-object-oriented-programming/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[_A_bstract classes, in short, are classes that are supposed to be inherited or subclassed, rather than instantiated.
Through Abstract Classes, we can enforce a blueprint on the subclasses that inherit the Abstract Class. This means that Abstract classes can be used to define a set of methods that must be implemented by it subclasses.
Abstract classes are used when working on large projects where classes have to be inherited, and need to strictly follow certain blueprints.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Magic methods and Syntactic sugar in Python</title>
    <link>https://arvimal.github.io/posts/2016/06/2016-06-02-magic-methods-in-python/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2016 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://arvimal.github.io/posts/2016/06/2016-06-02-magic-methods-in-python/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Magic methods _M_agic methods are special methods which can be defined (or already designed and available) to act on objects.
Magic methods start and end with underscores &quot;__&quot;, and are not implicitly called by the user even though they can be. Most magic methods are used as syntactic sugar by binding it to more clear/easy_to_understand keywords.
Python is mostly objects and method calls done on objects. Many available functions in Python are actually tied to magic methods_**.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Decorators - Object Oriented Programming</title>
    <link>https://arvimal.github.io/posts/2016/05/2016-05-30-decorators-object-oriented-programming/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2016 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://arvimal.github.io/posts/2016/05/2016-05-30-decorators-object-oriented-programming/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[_D_ecorators are wrapper functions (or classes) that wrap and modify another function (or class), and change it&rsquo;s behavior as required. Decorators help to modify your code without actually modifying the working function/class itself.
There are several inbuilt Decorators in Python, such as @classmethod and @staticmethod. Examples on these are due for another post.
Decorators are called to act upon a function or class, by mentioning the Decorator name just above the function/class.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Method Resolution Order - Object Oriented Programming</title>
    <link>https://arvimal.github.io/posts/2016/05/2016-05-30-method-resolution-order-object-oriented-programming/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2016 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://arvimal.github.io/posts/2016/05/2016-05-30-method-resolution-order-object-oriented-programming/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[_M_ethod Resolution Order or &lsquo;MRO&rsquo; in short, denotes the way a programming language resolves a method or attribute. This post looks into how Method Resolution Order works, using Python.
Python supports classes inheriting from other classes. The class being inherited is called the Parent/Super class, while the class that inherits is called the Child/Sub class.
While inheriting from another class, the interpreter needs a way to resolve the methods that are being called via an instance.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>range() and enumerate()</title>
    <link>https://arvimal.github.io/posts/2015/10/2015-10-12-range-and-enumerate-2/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2015 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://arvimal.github.io/posts/2015/10/2015-10-12-range-and-enumerate-2/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[The usual way to iterate over a range of numbers or a list in python, is to use range().
Example 0:
[code language=&ldquo;python&rdquo;] colors = [&ldquo;yellow&rdquo;, &ldquo;red&rdquo;, &ldquo;blue&rdquo;, &ldquo;white&rdquo;, &ldquo;black&rdquo;]
for i in range(len(colors)): print(i, colors[i]) [/code]
This should output:
[code language=&ldquo;bash&rdquo;] (0, &lsquo;yellow&rsquo;) (1, &lsquo;red&rsquo;) (2, &lsquo;blue&rsquo;) (3, &lsquo;white&rsquo;) (4, &lsquo;black&rsquo;) [/code]
print(), by default, returns a tuple. If we want to print it in a more presentable way, we’ll need to find the indice at which each value is, and print that as well.]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
