<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>monitors - Tag - The Child is Father of the Man</title>
        <link>https://arvimal.github.io/tags/monitors/</link>
        <description>monitors - Tag - The Child is Father of the Man</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>arvimal81@gmail.com (Vimal A.R)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>arvimal81@gmail.com (Vimal A.R)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 May 2016 00:00:00 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://arvimal.github.io/tags/monitors/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Ceph OSD heartbeats</title>
    <link>https://arvimal.github.io/ceph-osd-heartbeats/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2016 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Vimal A.R</author>
    <guid>https://arvimal.github.io/ceph-osd-heartbeats/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Ceph OSD daemons need to ensure that the neighbouring OSDs are functioning properly so that the cluster remains in a healthy state.
For this, each Ceph OSD process (ceph-osd) sends a heartbeat signal to the neighbouring OSDs. By default, the heartbeat signal is sent every 6 seconds [1], which is configurable of course.
If the heartbeat check from one OSD doesn&rsquo;t hear from the other within the set value for `osd_heartbeat_grace` [2], which is set to 20 seconds by default, the OSD that sends the heartbeat check reports the other OSD (the one that didn&rsquo;t respond within 20 seconds) as down, to the MONs.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Monitor maps, how to edit them?</title>
    <link>https://arvimal.github.io/2015-09-01-how-to-extract-view-change-and-inject-a-monitor-map-in-a-ceph-cluster/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Vimal A.R</author>
    <guid>https://arvimal.github.io/2015-09-01-how-to-extract-view-change-and-inject-a-monitor-map-in-a-ceph-cluster/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[The MON map is used by the monitors in a Ceph cluster, where they keep track of various attributes relevant to the working of the cluster.
Similar to the CRUSH map, a monitor map can be pulled out of the cluster, inspected, changed, and injected back to the monitors, manually. A frequent use-case is when the IP address of a monitor changes and the monitors cannot agree on a quorum.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Compacting a Ceph monitor store</title>
    <link>https://arvimal.github.io/compact-a-ceph-monitor-data-store/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2015 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Vimal A.R</author>
    <guid>https://arvimal.github.io/compact-a-ceph-monitor-data-store/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[The Ceph monitor store growing to a big size is a common occurrence in a busy Ceph cluster.
If a &lsquo;ceph -s&rsquo; takes considerable time to return information, one of the possibility is the monitor database being large.
Other reasons included network lags between the client and the monitor, the monitor not responding properly due to the system load, firewall settings on the client or monitor etc..
The best way to deal with a large monitor database is to compact the monitor store.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>How to list all the configuration settings in a Ceph cluster monitor?</title>
    <link>https://arvimal.github.io/list-ceph-cluster-configurations/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2015 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Vimal A.R</author>
    <guid>https://arvimal.github.io/list-ceph-cluster-configurations/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[It can be really helpful to have a single command to list all the configuration settings in a monitor node, in a Ceph cluster.
This is possible by interacting directly with the monitor&rsquo;s unix socket file. This can be found under /var/run/ceph/. By default, the admin socket for the monitor will be in the path /var/run/ceph/ceph-mon..asok.
The default location can vary in case you have defined it to be a different one, at the time of the installation.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
